<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science Portfolio on Jake Singleton</title>
    <link>https://jakesingi.github.io/jake_singleton/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science Portfolio on Jake Singleton</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2017 12:00:00 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jakesingi.github.io/jake_singleton/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 MLB Markov Chains for Run Scoring</title>
      <link>https://jakesingi.github.io/jake_singleton/projects/mlb-home-advantage/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakesingi.github.io/jake_singleton/projects/mlb-home-advantage/</guid>
      <description>In this project I model transitions between base-out states with Markov chains. I use 2021 MLB regular season data and repeatedly simulate half innings to create run distributions for all 24 base-out states. I discuss run expectancy and decision-making in baseball. Ultimately, I find two different Markov chains&amp;ndash;one for home teams and the other for away teams&amp;ndash;and estimate home field advantage to be half a run.
   Link to PDF Report Link to GitHub Repository  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tennis Ruminations &#43; Wimbledon Preview</title>
      <link>https://jakesingi.github.io/jake_singleton/projects/project-7/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakesingi.github.io/jake_singleton/projects/project-7/</guid>
      <description>Current tennis broadcasts are loaded with statistics, and it&amp;rsquo;s often hard to decipher which are most important. For example, we see graphics like the one here:
  We also see mid-match graphics, such as player tiebreak records when the match is headed for a tiebreak. (This one has always been a head-scratcher for me in particular, as I&amp;rsquo;ve wondered if tiebreak history is actually a good predictor of future tiebreak performance).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 NFL Ratings... and Why Choice of Loss Function Matters</title>
      <link>https://jakesingi.github.io/jake_singleton/projects/project-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakesingi.github.io/jake_singleton/projects/project-6/</guid>
      <description>In this project, I create 2020 NFL rankings based on the method described in Mathletics by Wayne Winston. I do so by scraping NFL game data in Python and creating team ratings using Microsoft Excel&amp;rsquo;s Solver tool. The relevant Python code and Excel files are all included in the GitHub Repo so that the reader may play around with the ratings if they like. The code is also thoroughly commented so that he/she may change things around as appropriate, and the Excel formulas are all pretty straightforward.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Four Factors: Statistics that Make College Basketball Teams Win</title>
      <link>https://jakesingi.github.io/jake_singleton/projects/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakesingi.github.io/jake_singleton/projects/project-5/</guid>
      <description>Calculates four factors for 30 NCAAMB teams from the 2019-2020 season. Teams are drawn from the 10 &amp;ldquo;high-major&amp;rdquo; conferences. Analysis features the use of linear regression to determine the importance of each factor. Results are compared to Dean Oliver and Wayne Winston&amp;rsquo;s NBA results. Data scraped from ESPN.
   Link to PDF Report Link to GitHub Repository  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Margot&#39;s Attempted Steal of Home</title>
      <link>https://jakesingi.github.io/jake_singleton/projects/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakesingi.github.io/jake_singleton/projects/project-4/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s World Series Game 5 with the series tied at 2. You&amp;rsquo;re standing on third with a teammate on first, you&amp;rsquo;re down by 1 in the bottom of the 4th with 2 outs, and future Hall of Famer Clayton Kershaw is on the mound. You&amp;rsquo;re a career 71% successful base stealer, and Kershaw&amp;rsquo;s back is to you as he brings his hands together above his head as he comes set. Do you steal home?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Exercise: Simulating the 2020 MLB Regular Season and Postseason</title>
      <link>https://jakesingi.github.io/jake_singleton/projects/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakesingi.github.io/jake_singleton/projects/project-3/</guid>
      <description>Shows how to simulate the 2020 MLB regular season and postseason. Generates regular season and postseason results using the Bradley-Terry model, specifically utilizing Pythagorean win percentage as estimates of teams&amp;rsquo; true talent levels. Strengths and weaknesses of the model are examined. Easily adaptable to other season formats.
   Link to PDF Report Link to GitHub Repository  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Exercise: Estimating the Exponent in Pythagorean Expectation</title>
      <link>https://jakesingi.github.io/jake_singleton/projects/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakesingi.github.io/jake_singleton/projects/project-2/</guid>
      <description>Presents a walkthrough of estimating the exponent in the Pythagorean expectation formula for win percentage. In this case, we use NBA data.
   Link to PDF Report Link to GitHub Repository  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stock Price Analysis Using Time Series!</title>
      <link>https://jakesingi.github.io/jake_singleton/projects/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakesingi.github.io/jake_singleton/projects/project-1/</guid>
      <description>Demonstrates data science life cycle in the following steps:
 EDA (visualizations) Transforming the data Removing the trend from the stock price data Fitting an ARIMA model to the residuals Selecting best model by cross validation Making and analyzing predictions.     Link to PDF Report Link to GitHub Repository  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>