<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Not So Normal on Jake Singleton</title>
    <link>https://jakesingi.github.io/jake_singleton/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Not So Normal on Jake Singleton</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jakesingi.github.io/jake_singleton/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Four Factors: Statistics that Make College Basketball Teams Win</title>
      <link>https://jakesingi.github.io/jake_singleton/projects/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakesingi.github.io/jake_singleton/projects/project-5/</guid>
      <description>Calculates four factors for 30 NCAAMB teams from the 2019-2020 season. Teams are drawn from the 10 &amp;ldquo;high-major&amp;rdquo; conferences. Analysis features the use of linear regression to determine the importance of each factor. Results are compared to Dean Oliver and Wayne Winston&amp;rsquo;s NBA results. Data scraped from ESPN.
  Link to GitHub Repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analyzing Margot&#39;s Attempted Steal of Home</title>
      <link>https://jakesingi.github.io/jake_singleton/projects/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakesingi.github.io/jake_singleton/projects/project-4/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s World Series Game 5 with the series tied at 2. You&amp;rsquo;re standing on third with a teammate on first, you&amp;rsquo;re down by 1 in the bottom of the 4th with 2 outs, and future Hall of Famer Clayton Kershaw is on the mound. You&amp;rsquo;re a career 71% successful base stealer, and Kershaw&amp;rsquo;s back is to you as he brings his hands together above his head as he comes set. Do you steal home?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Exercise: Simulating the 2020 MLB Regular Season and Postseason</title>
      <link>https://jakesingi.github.io/jake_singleton/projects/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakesingi.github.io/jake_singleton/projects/project-3/</guid>
      <description>Shows how to simulate the 2020 MLB regular season and postseason. Generates regular season and postseason results using the Bradley-Terry model, specifically utilizing Pythagorean win percentage as estimates of teams&amp;rsquo; true talent levels. Strengths and weaknesses of the model are examined. Easily adaptable to other season formats.
  Link to GitHub Repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fitness: Ring Muscle-Up</title>
      <link>https://jakesingi.github.io/jake_singleton/blog/muscle_up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakesingi.github.io/jake_singleton/blog/muscle_up/</guid>
      <description>Earlier today, I performed my first ring muscle-up. Finally achieving this movement is a huge accomplishment for me–it only took 4.5 months of training, countless YouTube videos, many failed attempts, and several reddit posts to finally get. The ring muscle-up is an advanced calisthenics move in which you grip a pair of gymnastics rings with a false grip, perform a pull-up, transition into the lower part of a dip, and then press yourself up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R Exercise: Estimating the Exponent in Pythagorean Expectation</title>
      <link>https://jakesingi.github.io/jake_singleton/projects/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakesingi.github.io/jake_singleton/projects/project-2/</guid>
      <description>Presents a walkthrough of estimating the exponent in the Pythagorean expectation formula for win percentage. In this case, we use NBA data.
  Link to GitHub Repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stock Price Analysis Using Time Series!</title>
      <link>https://jakesingi.github.io/jake_singleton/projects/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakesingi.github.io/jake_singleton/projects/project-1/</guid>
      <description>Demonstrates data science life cycle in the following steps:
 EDA (visualizations) Transforming the data Removing the trend from the stock price data Fitting an ARIMA model to the residuals Selecting best model by cross validation Making and analyzing predictions.    Link to GitHub Repository</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://jakesingi.github.io/jake_singleton/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jakesingi.github.io/jake_singleton/contact/</guid>
      <description>Feel free to reach out to me via social media or email!
   Platform Link     Twitter: https://twitter.com/jakesingi   LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jake-singleton/   GitHub: https://github.com/jakesingi   Email: jake.singleton@berkeley.edu    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>